我们夜里行军 黎明时分
We march at nightfall, and by dawn's light,
就能抓到斯巴达克斯了
see an end to Spartacus.
有信号
The signal.
葛雷博
Glaber?
再来
Again!
撤进地道
Fall back into the tunnel.
走 快走
Move, move!
走山路 快
The mountain path, hurry!
我们被包围了
We'll be trapped.
没办法了 我们必须走
There's no choice. We must move!
你打算放过他们吗
You will let them go free?
不 我要把他们赶尽杀绝
No, we shall kill them all.
《斯巴达克斯：复仇》
《神谴》
柴火快用完了
The wood for fire is almost gone.
吃的也不多了
Our food quickly follows.
自打葛雷博把我们逼到山里以来
We have stripped the mountain of what little it had
能找到的东西就这么点了
ever since Glaber forced us upon it.
不该发生这样的事
A thing that should not have happened.
你一定能想到办法摆脱困境
You will find a way to see us from this.
你总能想到办法
You always do.
而在我丧失信心的时候
As you always find words,
你的话总是能鼓励我
to pull me from darkest thoughts.
希望你的新欢也有这个本事
A talent I pray your next woman holds.
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus!
纳美特斯人和一群傻子出动了
Nemetes and a clutch of fools have taken a foot.
去干什么
Towards what purpose?
他们要冲到山下杀出罗马人的重围
They attempt to breach the Romans at the foot of the path.
下次打个招呼
Give word next time.
还以为你是敌人呢
Be mistaken as enemy.
葛雷博找你
Glaber summons you.
我们刚吃完世界上最好吃的羊肉
We only just finished dining on the most succulent lamb.
说不定还剩了点肉渣
There may yet be few scraps left.
说话别太过分
You overstep,...
奴隶
slave.
我只是听民政官差遣办事
I but place foot where our praetor commands.
你要是有意见
If you do not care for where it falls, ...
尽管提出来
you are free to take issue.
操你妈 你个混蛋
我听不懂你说什么
I do not know your tongue.
也没有学的打算
Nor have cause to learn it.
撤退
Pull back!
快走
Go! Move!
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus!
米拉
Mira!
我们得赶紧撤
We must go!
米拉
Mira!
我们得给她止血
We must seal her wound!
纳西尔 用火把你的剑烧热
Nasir! Heat your sword in the fire!
快点
Quickly!
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus...
你觉得值得吗
Was it worth it?
值得赔上她的性命
Was it worth... her life,
来救你们几个吗
to make attempt to save your own?!
别他妈跟着掺和
Stay your fucking ground.
她死了都是因为你
She is gone from this world cause of you!
是你这个王八蛋把我们带到死路上的
You are the mad fuck that led us to our deaths!
最起码她堂堂正正死在战场上
At least she claimed hers as a warrior.
而不像我们一样
Not starving and robbed of strength,
早晚在这儿饿死
as the rest of us are doomed.
你说的对
You are right.
我们面前确实是死路一条
We will all perish.
如果我们不能同心协力的话
If we do not stand together.
你他妈说这些废话有屁用
It will make no fucking difference.
闭嘴 竖起你的狗耳朵好好听着
Seize tongue, and open fucking ears.
维苏威的悬崖上根本无路可走
The cliffs of Vesuvius are impassable.
只有往南才有一线生机
The southern path holds the only promise of making purchase.
我们占领了制高点
We hold the higher ground,
正好可以弥补人数的不足
and with it advantage over superior numbers.
好像葛雷博真会傻到来攻打似的
Only if Glaber is foolish enough to attack.
不等他来 我们就都饿得没力气了
Before we are too weak from hunger to fight.
饥饿和伤痛
A man is never too weak...
永远不是畏战的借口
or too wounded to fight.
生命诚可贵 自由价更高
If the cause is greater than his own life.
葛雷博的大军迟早会来
Glaber and his army will come.
等他们来的时候
And when they do,
就准备迎接复仇的怒火
Vesuvius will be forever stained...
血染维苏威
with the blood of vengeance.
就抓住他一个吗
He is all that was captured?
还有几个死了
Several more lay dead.
活着算你走运
A fortunate thing you are not among them.
要不是我跟埃及人在场
Had that Egyptian and I not been present,
据点就失守了
I fear position would have been overrun.
看来是诸神保佑
The gods favor us then.
不再庇护那些伤害我们的人了
And turn from those who would do us harm.
跟我说说斯巴达克斯
Tell me of Spartacus,...
他对即将到来的暴风雨有什么想法
and his thoughts toward coming storm.
你个罗马败类也就配舔老子的屁股
他会说人话吗
Can he form proper words?
目前看好像不会
He has yet to break them.
看老子不在你头上撒泡尿
果真一句人话都不会说
A most unpleasant tongue.
形势一定很严峻
Conditions must be dire,
他们才会冒险下山 放弃制高点
to abandon the higher ground and attempt at such foolish act.
不过好像不是斯巴达克斯指挥的
One that did not appear commanded by Spartacus.
你亲眼看见他了
You laid eyes upon the man?
一眼而已 他和那帮杂碎救走了其余的人
Briefly, as he and his... shits gave opportunities for others to retreat.
他看起来怎么样
How did he appear?
要命
Deadly.
我看到他的眼神
Yet there was a look about eye.
就像一只狂野的猛兽
One found reflected in wild beast,
在做困兽之斗
when pressed to corner.
这头畜生
Such an animal...
不见棺材不掉泪
never greets the afterlife absent desperate blood.
维苏威火山可不是百宝箱
Vesuvius is not Cere's Horn,
可以取之不尽用之不竭
offering endless bounty.
那寸草不生的荒山上 根本没有什么可吃的
There cannot be much in way of nourishment left upon barren peak.
我们就等一阵子再动手
We shall stay our hand yet a while longer.
等他们饥寒交迫
And when hunger and despair
奄奄一息的时候
are the only tastes upon his lips,
斯巴达克斯必将跪倒在罗马脚下
Spartacus shall kneel before Rome...
永不翻身
for e final time.
我们不应该上路
We should not be upon road.
回去吧
Let us turn back.
不行
No.
我不愿意每天无所事事地待在卡普亚
I will not sit idle in Capua as weeks threaten unwelcome months.
很快就能等到头了
All will soon come to an end.
我已经等不及了
I would see the day hastened.
我要让孩子出生在
And my child born in a city
民政官之子应该出生的地方
befitting the heir of a praetor.
你马上就要临产了
The glorious occasion is almost upon us.
这时候冒险去罗马
To risk the journey to Rome...
还有时间
There was yet time.
只要我说服丈夫加快进攻的步伐
If my husband is moved to bring siege against Spartacus
早点结束此事
to early conclusion.
所以我们才去维苏威
The reason we are for Vesuvius.
一部分原因
A fraction of it.
其实我还有更加迫切的需要
The whole of the truth encompassing greater need.
这么说他的心已经回到你身上了
Has heart returned so fiercely in such regard?
盖尤斯和我是一条心
Gaius and I share but one now.
他不在身边就感觉少了什么东西
His absence leaving chest but half filled.
能够重新回到夫君的怀抱
To find yourself in the arms of a husband thought lost.
真是天大的福气
That's a blessing beyond measure.
我怎么会忘了最好的朋友呢
A happiness I would share with a treasured friend.
我会带你去罗马
You will come with me to Rome.
让盖尤斯给你准备一笔可观的嫁妆
I will entreat Gaius towards dowry in honor of your service,
然后你再找一位如意郎君相伴
and you shall again find comfort in title of wife.
你丈夫是不会让我陪你去的
Your husband would not have me follow with you.
你对他的帮助那么大
You have been invaluable to his cause.
他看重的是另一个人
He believes another more so.
他答应把我送给阿舒尔
I have been promised to Ashur.
阿舒尔
Ashur?
你丈夫为奖励他的犬马之劳
My hand and house, in payment
把我和这间宅子一并赏给他
for blood spilled in your husband's name.
你怎么不早跟我说
Why have you not told me this?
你产期将近 我不愿意跟你说
I would not have such thoughts weigh mind and body,
这么沉重的话题
with your day so close at hand.
不过我打算在维苏威
I will seize opportunity at Vesuvius,
解除掉后顾之忧
and attempt to rid myself of burden.
说出来
Reveal intentions.
我帮你办
And see them embraced.
我们坐在这儿等死 他却在摆弄那些杂草
We sit here waiting to die, and he tends to fucking weeds.
他那是太伤心了
He tends to his heart.
人之常情
As any man should.
这里没有足够的柴火给她火葬
There is not enough wood to build a pyre.
土地又太硬 不能安葬她
The ground is too hard to lay her beneath it.
他只能伤心地用斗篷给她裹尸
He can only grieve, and bind her in his cloak.
那敢情好
A blessing then.
不等她腐烂我们就全死翘翘了
That we shall all be dead before she turns overly ripe.
纳美特斯人他们越来越不安了
Nemetes and his kind grow ever more restless.
恐怕不光他们这么想
I fear they're not alone.
不怪他们
I cannot lay blame.
但我们唯一的机会就是在战术上击溃对手
Yet our only chance of survival is to hold fast to sound tactic.
就像上次区区几个人偷袭竞技场吗
Like attacking the arena with a handful of men?
我以前觉得你是一介莽夫
I once thought you reckless fool.
现在我知道了 你之所以还没挂
Now I see bold strategy is the only reason
全凭你有勇有谋
you're not already dead.
那是运气好 抓住了
I have been but fortunate, to have
罗马人完全想不到的那种机会
seized opportunity the Romans would consider mad.
这次我们没有机会
There stand none left to us now,
除非长翅膀飞出去
absent wings to fly from cliff.
我们和葛雷博的军队正面决战的那一天
The day comes when we must face Glaber and his army
就要到了
in open battle.
就算死了
If I am to die,
至少有兄弟们陪着
at least I shall die among brothers.
我们算是兄弟
We share a bond.
不是角斗士那种
Forged not upon the sands,
但在战场里摸爬滚打过
but upon grander stage of battle.
等事情完了
And when it ends,
作为犒赏 巴蒂塔斯的训练场和宅子归我了
I will gain Batiatus's ludus and villa as reward for loyal service.
到时候在阿舒尔家族里
It will become the noble House of Ashur,
要训练出整个共和国
where I shall train the mightiest gladiators
最强的角斗士
in all the Republic.
你们就是我的第一批战将
I would count you among my first recruits.
只要你们发誓 保证…
I ask but for your oath, pledging
打开大门
Open the gate!
在这儿等着
Wait here.
保证免除你的后顾之忧
And see weighted heart lifted.
再没动静了吗
There has been no further movement?
斯巴达克斯已经知道突围只是徒劳
We have taught Spartacus the futility of attempting breach.
让疯狗不露牙齿是不现实的
You cannot school rabid dog not to bare teeth.
伊莉西娅
Ilithyia!
你不该来的
You should not have come.
我知道 规矩嘛
Yes, I know, the rules.
女人不能来营地
Women are forbidden in the encampment.
我只是担心你和你肚子里的孩子
My concern is only for you, and the life you carry.
我不想让你这样子奔波劳累
I would not have you travel in such condition.
我感觉好极了
I have never felt stronger.
再远的路程都没问题呢
And would...travel a greater distance still.
你想回罗马
You wish to return to Rome.
跟我夫君一起
With my husband beside me.
叛徒们开始绝望了
The rebels become desperate.
再过几周 等他们饿得半死…
A few more weeks from starvation
再过几周 你的继承人就会
A few more weeks and your heir will be born
在满是血迹和屎尿的地方出生了
in a house tainted with blood and shit.
杀掉斯巴达克斯
End Spartacus's life.
然后我们一起回家
And let us return home to ours.
他占据了高地
He holds the higher ground.
现在要拿下他们 我们势必伤亡惨重
It cannot be taken yet without severe loss of men.
但是
Yet,
可以拿下他们吧
it can be taken?
回卡普亚等我
Await me in Capua.
准备庆祝我们的孩子降生在…
And prepare to celebrate the birth of our child...
罗马母亲的怀抱里
in the arms of mother Rome.
你真是威风凛凛 顶天立地
You truly stand a titan, threatening the very heavens.
去吧
Go.
记得我心里有你
And know that you are in my thoughts.
还有件事要告诉你
I would linger but a moment longer.
这是什么
What is this?
警示
A warning.
诸神的警示
From the gods.
你怎么拿到这个的
How did this come to you?
我在清理赛皮娅的痕迹时发现的
I uncovered it while cleansing trace of Seppia.
就藏在她的物品里
Secreted among her things.
我的奴隶阿玛纳看到有人给她这个东西
My slave Amana recalls seeing it pressed into Seppia's hands.
就是那个叙利亚混蛋
By the Syrian toad.
所以她知道哥哥死在你手里
That is how she knew her brother's true fate.
所以她要杀你
And why she moved against you.
没道理啊
But it holds no sense.
阿舒尔的命运握在我的手里
Ashur's fortunes are tethered to my own.
他是条毒蛇
He is a serpent,
一刻不停地觊觎权力和地位
forever seeking the heat of power and position.
当瓦里留斯危及你的地位时
When yours was threatened by Varinius,
他倒戈一击 卖主求荣 不算奇怪吧
is it a wonder he sought to slither towards warmer clime?
他终究是卑鄙小人
A venomous creature to the last.
那家伙没什么价值了
One no longer holding worth.
还有一个家伙也没有价值了
He is not alone, in such regard.
毒蛇也好 神使也罢 如今不需要他们了
Serpents and oracle have both served purpose.
你是说露迪雅
You speak of Lucretia?
我说的是一个知道很多秘密的女人
I speak of a woman who knows secrets I would not have revealed.
你要我动手办这件事吗
You would ask me to do such a thing?
我只想要那些不幸成为过去
I would put unfortunate past behind us,
我们共迎美好的未来
and seize glorious future.
真想念你的香味啊
I have missed your delicate scent...
还有那些让我特别兴奋的事情
among other offerings of more personal nature.
看到你来了 我真是高兴
It lifts spirits, to find you close again.
我一会儿就走
I stay but a moment.
无关紧要
A thing of low importance,
反正我们还有一辈子的时间
when set against the promise of a lifetime
可以相互依偎
held in loving embrace.
分手的时候不用难过
Will not shed tear when we part.
要知道这场战斗很快就要结束
Know that campaign soon draws to inevitable close.
我阿舒尔就要上位了
And Ashur to deserving reward.
万分期待那一天的到来
I long to greet the day.
叙利亚人
Syrian.
你以为我傻吗
Do you think me the fool?
大人
Praetor?
我不明白
I do not understand.
这不是你拿的吗
Do you deny taking it?
我从死人身上拿过很多东西
I take many things from the fallen.
这都是托您的福
I thought I had your blessing to do so.
你还去找过赛皮娅托福吧
And did you also seek Seppia's blessing,
所以她企图刺杀我
before she made attempt on my life?
赛皮娅
Seppia?
我从未跟那姑娘说过话
I've never broken words with the girl.
我听够了毒蛇的谎言
I have had my fill of serpent's tongue.
等等
Wait!
我不知道别人跟您说了什么
I do not know what you have been told,
不过恐怕您犯了严重的错误
but I fear you have made a grave error.
恐怕犯错的人是你
Now I fear you have made the error.
不知天高地厚 跟你的主子作对
In attempting to maneuver beyond your station.
可惜这么好的合作 落得如此结局
Unfortunate end to profitable association.
不如我带着他们就此离开
Perhaps it best my men and I quietly take leave,
以免伤了和气
absent further disagreement.
我有更好的提议
Oh I would make better offer.
只要愿意效忠于我
Land and a thousand denarii to each of you,
每人赐土地和一千第纳尔
in return for faithful service.
你们这些贱货
You fucking cunts.
且慢
Hold.
你曾对我宣誓效忠
You once swore to me.
说什么"任您吩咐"
"Your will, my hands.."
我的誓言从未动摇过
An oath that has not wavered!
我对您发誓 民政官大人
I swear it to you, praetor!
那我就试试你这些鬼话
I would test such vaunted words.
还有你的忠诚是真是假
And the depths of your loyalty.
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus!
山路上有动静
There's movement upon the path.
就位
Take position!
阿舒尔
Ashur!
我是替葛雷博传话来的
I come bearing message from Glaber!
说吧
Speak it.
他已经厌倦了这种对峙
He has grown weary of this conflict.
想赶回罗马让孩子顺利降生
And would return home to see his child born in Rome.
关我屁事
A thing of no interest.
可能关系到你们的命
Perhaps the lives of your people hold more.
他提出了投降条件
He offers terms of surrender.
放下武器 就饶你们不死
Lay down your arms, you'll be allowed to live.
让我们做奴隶吗
As slaves?
跪在共和国的脚下
Beneath the heel of the Republic?
是的 做奴隶
Yes, as slaves.
但你们能活命
Yet you will have your lives!
如果拒绝 葛雷博发誓
Refuse, and Glaber has sworn torturous death
攻下山头后
upon the cross for all
就把你们活生生钉死在十字架上
that survives the taking of the mountain!
那斯巴达克斯的性命呢
And what of Spartacus's life?
作为交易的筹码
The cost of the bargain.
我今天可不想死
I for one do not wish to die this day.
不过相比这么窝囊地活
Yet if it is to be fucking so,
我宁愿自由地死
I shall do it as a free man!
狗日的罗马人
Fuck the Romans!
坚决不投降
No surrender!
叙利亚杂种
Syrian cunt!
你听到答案了
You have your answer.
很好
Very well...
我会把话原封不动地带给他
I shall deliver it to waiting ears.
你先别急着走
I would not have us part so quickly.
葛雷博等着我 我必须
Glaber awaits, I must return
给他答复
with a reply.
你的项上人头同样能答复他
Your head would serve equal purpose.
斯巴达克斯
Spartacus...
他说的合情合理
I find no fault with his reasoning.
威猛的克雷斯 名垂千古的
The mighty Crixus, forever intoning
伟大的角斗士
of the honor of a gladiator.
现在不顾体面
Where stands such now,
要欺负一个手无寸铁的人
in the cutting down of a defenseless man?
给他一把剑
Give him a sword.
你以前渴望能上场角斗
You once dreamt of honor upon the sand.
这就算你的最后一战吧
Make this your final arena.
你贵为冠军 而我伤势严重
You stand a champion, and I gravely wounded.
这场战斗毫无荣誉可言
There is yet no honor in such contest.
去他妈的荣誉
To shit with honor.
不要
No.
我不要你玷污名誉
I will not have you soil name,
来为我报仇
to gain vengeance in mine.
妮维雅
Naevia...
我自己解决
I shall take it myself.
阿舒尔对我的伤害无人可比
No one has been more wronged by Ashur.
没有人比我更有资格取他的狗命
And no one has greater claim on his fucking life.
我要亲手送他上西天
I will see him fall.
连同那段黑暗的回忆一并消灭
And with him memories that haunt darkest nights.
交给你了
See it done.
你确定让她上
Are you certain of this?
我听她的
I am far removed.
很好
Very well.
如果今天阿舒尔必死
If Ashur must die today,
起码要先送克雷斯的婊子下地狱
at least he will see Crixus's bitch to the afterlife before him.
砍下他的脑袋
Take his fucking head off!
娇嫩的花朵长出刺来了
Delicate flower has grown thorns.
你可以打败他 妮维雅
You can take him, Naevia!
杀掉这个畜生
Kill the cunt!
不败的高卢人亲手磨砺的尖刺
Sharpened by the undefeated Gaul.
恐怕没什么用
I fear it will not help.
花朵凋谢了
She fades.
一切美丽的东西都不可避免
As all beautiful things do.
妮维雅
Naevia!
别出手
No!
他是我的对手
He is mine.
退后
Stay back!
我要让他为自己的罪行付出代价
I will have his life for what he did to me.
死不足惜
Or die in attempt!
上啊 加把劲
Go! Come on!
你还记得吗
Do you recall this?
我紧紧压着你的胴体
My body pressed against yours?
你没用地颤抖着 跟现在一样
You trembling helpless, as you tremble now
谁说我没用
I am far from helpless.
你觉得这样做有改变吗
You think this makes difference?
我的死不会愈合你的伤口
My death will not heal the scars you bear.
也不会抹去你被我玩弄的回忆
Nor erase memory of my cock inside of her,
还有无数人的奸淫
or all those that followed.
是的
No.
我忘不掉
It will not.
这只是一个开始
But it is a fucking start.
你说的对
You were right.
确实不容易
It is no easy task.
一剑把人的脑袋砍下来
To cleave a man's head from his shoulders in a single blow.
那我来教你
Then I will teach you.
多纳 莱顿
Donar! Lydon!
把阿舒尔的脑袋放到路上
See Ashur's head upon the path,
当作给葛雷博的回应
as reply to Glaber.
你这回应真够明确
You send a clear one.
活着的人要钉死在十字架上了
It will be nail and cross for those who live.
葛雷博肯定会这样对待我们
Glaber would have seen us all to such fate,
不管我们作何回应
regardless of answer carried.
就是说我们横竖都得死
So we are dead either way.
可惜没那么多树藤给我们的尸体用
Pity there are not enough vines for all our corpses.
闭上你们的鸟嘴
Close fucking mouth.
不 纳美特斯人说的对
No. Nemetes is right.
树藤确实不够我们所有人用
There are not enough vines for us all.
但对几个人来说 还是绰绰有余
And perhaps there's enough for a few.
你这话什么意思
Your words carry no meaning.
在葛雷博看来 正常的军队
Glaber expects us to defend the higher ground,
应该扼守高地
as any reasonable leader would.
不过我们可以另辟蹊径
Yet perhaps there is another course.
一步险棋 罗马人绝对想不到
A bold one, that the Romans will never see coming.
民政官大人
Praetor.
他们已经给出了回应
They have given reply.
斯巴达克斯果然这么做了
Spartacus makes expected choice.
传令下去 让全军吃好睡好
Tell the men to eat well and gather sleep.
黎明伊始 我们就要拿下维苏威
Dawn's first light we take Vesuvius
杀光所有胆敢藐视罗马的逆贼
and the lives of all those who stand in defiance of Rome.
我们就要离开这里了
Soon we shall leave this place.
再也不回来
Never to return.
你对我的友情
What your friendship brings me...
难以用语言表达我的感激
there are no words to express gratitude.
你已经回报了许多
You have returned the favor many times over.
你的恩情我根本无法报答
The debt I owe far exceeds modest repayment.
是你把我从疯狂的边缘拉了回来
You drew me from the depth of madness.
是你给了我力量和信念
You gave me strength and purpose
我才能走出那场惨剧的阴影
to live beyond the tragedy which betided this house.
过去的已经过去了
Such things are of the past.
不要再为那些事伤心了
Let them give you no further pain.
我也尝试过不去想
I have tried to put it from me.
可那些痛苦的记忆
The memory of all I have lost,
仍弥漫在空气中
it fills the very air,
每次呼吸都能感到刺痛
choking each breath with the sting of loss.
牢牢地束缚我的心
And binding my heart in chains.
你就快解脱了
You stand upon precipice of release.
因为你
Because of you.
你是我的救星 伊莉西娅
You're my savior, Ilithyia.
你也是我的救星
And you mine.
你给了我生活的希望
You have given me hope of a life
丈夫死时我以为一切都结束了
I thought denied me when my husband fell.
如此贵重的礼物应该永远珍藏
Know that such a gift shall be eternally treasured.
孩子
The child.
马上就要生了
It comes too soon.
这是诸神的旨意
This is a sign from the gods!
你的孩子必须在里面出生
It must be born within these walls.
过来
Come.
让我们实现诸神的意志
Let us see their will be done.
我们已经用上了所有能找到的树藤
We have used every vine we could gather.
够四个人下山
Enough for four men.
艾力冈 克雷斯 甘尼克斯
Agron. Crixus. Gannicus.
我要你们一起行动
I would have you by my side.
克雷斯
Crixus...
我们很快就能重聚
We will be reunited soon.
无论今生 还是来世
In this life, or the next.
我知道你们胸怀恐惧
I know fear wells within your breast.
这种想法很正常
And it does so with great cause.
罗马军队的人数远远超过我们
The Romans hold numbers far outweighing our own.
但他们一次次地暴露出致命的弱点
Yet they have revealed time and again fatal flaw.
即他们相信打仗只有用罗马人的方式
That they believe the Roman way is the only one.
正如他们相信离开这座山
Just as they believe that there is only one way
只有一条路
to leave this mountain.
我们去教教他们
We shall teach them
路是可以亲手开辟的
that we forge our own paths.
只要有决心和信念
And nothing in this world is impossible,
世上没有不可能的事
when heart and mind are put towards it.
拉绳
Brace rope,
这一堂课要教他们永生难忘
let us begin a lesson forever remembered.
雷声可以掩护这次行动
The sound will mask descent.
诸神赐给我们大好良机
The gods bless us with good fortune.
自由人自己创造机会
Free men create their own.
今夜我们就是神
We are all gods this night.
让罗马人感受到众神的愤怒
And the Romans shall feel our wrath.
操
Fuck!
大家准备好
Prepare yourselves.
看到信号
When signal comes...
就要玩命了
death shall quickly follow.
我们得快点行动
We must move quickly.
别等他们发现了
Before deed is discovered.
时辰已晚
The hour is late.
睡不着了
Sleep will not come.
只要我一闭眼
All I see when eyes close
就看到斯巴达克斯的下场
is the end of Spartacus.
我因为此事离开罗马这么久
And with him reason for being so long absent from Rome,
还有很多重要的事情等着做
and more important matters.
瓦里留斯失败了 而您凯旋而归
You will be victorious, where Varinius failed.
这是您在元老院的资本
A great advantage within the Senate.
借此平步青云
To be used towards elevation.
总有一天 我要置身于万人之上
One day I shall rise above all others.
以如此辉煌的成就
The light of accomplishment giving warmth
荫庇我的爱妻和爱子
to loving wife and cherished heir...
发警报
Raise alarm!
遵命
Praetor!
快集合军队
Gather the men to formation!
叫醒他们
Awake the men!
发射
Fire!
看到信号了
The signal!
该死的医师死哪儿去了
Where the fuck is the medicus?!
他进城了
He had gone to town,
谁料到孩子这么早出生
the child not expected for weeks.
我派卫兵去找他了
I have sent the guards to fetch him.
感觉不太对
Something is wrong.
小家伙在抓我
It claws at me,
好像不愿意离开子宫 在这里降生
not wanting to leave womb to be born in this place.
我去找东西帮你止痛
I will find something to ease the pain.
别离开我
Do not leave me.
我会回来的
Know that I will return.
和你一同见证诸神的赐福
And together we will see this blessing into the world.
再来
Again!
这里需要支援
I need help over here!
把弹药搬走
Relocate ammunition.
保持阵型前进
Advance on rear position!
胆敢阻拦的人 全都杀无赦
Kill anyone in who stands in your path!
停
Halt!
杀个痛快
A glorious death.
杀掉他们
Kill them!
我好像听到了尖叫声
I thought I heard a cry
你做了什么
What have you done?
一直以来想做的事
What was always intended,
消除这间宅子蒙受的诅咒
to see curse upon this house lifted.
没有人阻碍我们俩了
No one left to come between us.
撤退
Fall back!
一鼓作气 胜利是我们的
Press advantage! And see victory ours!
住手
Stop.
求你了
Please.
我们是朋友 不是吗
We are friends, are we not?
闺中密友
The very best.
那你为什么要做这些
Then why would you do this?
为什么要夺去我和孩子的生命
Why would you take my life and that of my child?
你的孩子
Your child?
你不过是工具
You are but a vessel.
承载着诸神赐予巴蒂塔斯家族的厚礼
Carrying a gift from the gods to the House of Batiatus.
那么
Now then.
我们可以打开了
Let us see it unwrapped...
这是还给你的
I owe you pain.
奥诺玛默斯
Oenomaus!
Oenomaus...
我要回到妻子的怀抱了
I go to my wife's arms.
兄弟 我们在另一个世界等着你
We shall greet you in the afterlife, my brother.
四处警戒
Secure the perimeter!
号令全军防御此地
Signal all men to defend this position.
各就各位
Mark your stations!
罗马战士做好准备
Romans ready!
露迪雅
Lucretiaaaaaaa!
小宝贝 别哭了
Hush now little one.
你没事了
You are safe now.
有人爱你
You are loved,
直到永远
and shall be forever.
求你了
Please.
昆图斯一直想要个儿子
Quintus always wanted a son.
多亏了你
Because of you,
我们终于能实现愿望
we shall have one.
不
No.
我绝不会
I will not die
死在奴隶的手里
at the hands of a fucking slave!
我是自由人
I am a free man.
这个罗马人总算搞清楚了他的地位
The Roman finally learns his place before us!
跪在我们面前
On his knees!
你根本没赢
You've won nothing.
罗马即将派出大军为我报仇
Rome will send legions in my wake.
终有一天 你们会死无葬身之地
And one day soon you shall fall to deserved end.
也许吧
Perhaps.
但绝不是今天
Yet it is not this day.
罗马大军尽管来吧
Let Rome send their legions!
我们迎接挑战
We will face them!
要他们全都步葛雷博的后尘
And see all follow Glaber in death!
好啊
Yeah!
我们就要成为一支军队了
Now we will become an army.
好啊
Yeah!
斯巴达克斯 斯巴达克斯
Spartacus! Spartacus! Spartacus! Spartacus!